pulse360.com 2016-06-08

# Pulse360

Privacy Policy

Pulse 360 Network Privacy Policy 

At Pulse 360, we take your privacy seriously and do all we can to protect your privacy while using our site and other services available through our site. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect and use information about you as you utilize any Pulse 360 services, including the adverting services we provide to businesses that have their own web sites (our "Advertising Network"). Information practices relating to our own web site (www.pulse360.com) are addressed in a separate privacy policy, which you can review [here](http://www.pulse360.com/site-privacy.html). Pulse 360 acknowledges that adherence to fair information collection practices is of utmost importance is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and work with industry-leading companies to address important privacy and consumer protection issues in online advertising. To learn more about the NAI, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

When you use web sites in our Advertising Network, we may at times deliver advertising targeted to meet your specific interests through the use of cookies and by using non-personally identifiable information ("Non-PII") about you and your specific interests and behavior online. We feel that this offers you a more relevant and enjoyable advertising experience. You are encouraged to carefully review the section below entitled "[Pulse Targeted Advertising and How to Opt-out](http://www.pulse360.com/#optout)" to learn more about this practice, and to learn how to opt-out if you do not want your Non-PII used for this type of advertising. 

This Privacy Policy is subject to change, so we encourage you to visit this page frequently to review our practices. By using any web sites that are part of our Advertising Network, you indicate that you agree to the collection and use of your information by Pulse 360 as outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

First and foremost, Pulse 360 collects Non-PII to improve the services we provide and to present you with advertising that will be more suited to your interests. We also use your Non-PII to measure our success and performance. For example, Non-PII we gather gives us an idea of the number of visitors to our Advertising Network and how they navigate our Advertising Network. 

We do not collect personal information from web sites on our Advertising Network. Please note that the businesses that own web sites in our Advertising Network may separately collect personal information and such collection would be governed by the privacy policy of the applicable web site. However, we do not receive any personal information relating to site users from sites in our Advertising Network. 

As we provide services to businesses in our Advertising Network, we may automatically collect Non-PII, such as site pages viewed, browser type, computer information, cookie data, clickstream data and other information. This Non-PII is analyzed and may be combined or compared with aggregate information or similar information of other users and may be collected and on numerous web sites in our Advertising Network. Such Non-PII is anonymous and does not identify any individual user. We may freely share Non-PII with our business partners and other third parties. Further, we may disclose, use and authorize the use of your Non-PII in any manner permitted by law and this Privacy Policy, including for the following general purposes: provision and enhancement of our services, marketing, research and to more effectively match advertisements and website content to your interests. 

"Cookies" are small data files that are sent to your browser and are stored on your hard drive, keeping track of your general activity on a site. When you make subsequent visits to a web site on our Advertising Network, your cookie gives us a summary of your preferences and past experiences on the site. This allows us to tailor Pulse 360 services on our Advertising Network. Your cookie may be altered at different times throughout your visits to web sites in our Advertising Network, and it is updated frequently as you encounter various Pulse 360 features and services on sites in our Advertising Network. 

Pixel tags (also known as "action tags," or "web beacons") are small strings of code that provide a method for delivering a graphic image on a site and which allow the operator of the site, or a third party who serves the pixel tag, to set, read, and modify cookies on, and to transfer other data to, the browser used to view the site. Pixel tags may also be used to obtain information about the computer being used to view that site. The entity that sends the tag can view the IP address of the computer that the tag is sent to, the time it was sent, the user's operating system and browser type, and similar information. We use pixel tags on our Advertising Network. 

Every time you use a site on our Advertising Network, our server may deliver certain customized information to you based on the data stored in your cookie. You may opt-out of our cookie-based targeted advertising ("Pulse Targeted Advertising Program"). [Click here](http://www.pulse360.com/behavior/opt.html) to view/change your preferences for the Pulse Targeted Advertising Program. You may also [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) for the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) opt-out tool to opt out of certain behavior targeting programs not associated with Pulse 360. Note that if you opt out of the Pulse 360 Targeted Advertising Program using the NAI opt-tool or our opt-out tool, your browser must be set to accept cookies. If you clear your browser's cookies, use a different computer, use a different browser on the same computer, or delete your cookies, you may need to opt out again. 

Further, you should note that although most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, you may be able to change your browser settings to cause your browser to refuse third-party cookies or to indicate when a third-party cookie is being sent. Check your browser's "Help" files or other similar resources to learn more about handling cookies on your browser. 

We may use third party advertising technology providers to serve advertisements and provide other services in connection with our Advertising Network. These services may include the use of web beacons, web bugs, action tags, pixels and third party cookies which read our cookies, or visa-versa, or involve the use of anonymous supplemental information (described below). To opt-out of certain behavior targeting programs not associated with Pulse 360, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) for the NAI opt-out tool. 

"Clickstream data" is a trail of electronic information that is left at each web site you visit. This information can be collected and stored by a site's server. We may, for example, use clickstream data to tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use, the address of the site from which you linked to a site in our Advertising Network, how much time you spend on each page of a site, how you navigate throughout the site and how we may tailor advertisements or pages of sites in our Advertising Network to better meet the needs of our business partners. 

Our services are maintained in the United States of America. By using web sites in our Advertising Network, you freely and specifically authorize us to export any information that is gathered in accordance with this Privacy Policy to the USA and you authorize storage and use as specified in this Privacy Policy. 

In order for the Advertising Network to perform properly and as necessary to enhance our services, we may supplement the information we receive on a site with information from third party sources. For example, we may combine cookie data gathered on sites in our Advertising Network with cookie data from a third party in order to improve our services. Any information that we acquire from a third party which is combined with your information will be handled as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

Sites in our Advertising Network and sites linked to from those sites may have privacy policies and practices that are different from ours. For example, sites in our Advertising Network have their own privacy policies and their own practices. Collection or use of information by these parties is beyond Pulse 360's control and is not covered by this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every site you visit before providing any information. 

Pulse 360 stores all data using industry standard security devices, such as firewalls and encryption protocols, to prevent against unauthorized access to our data. We have put in place reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. We have put in place policies to restrict access to your information by our employees. However, Pulse 360 cannot guarantee that your information will be completely protected from unauthorized access and you assume such risk when you use any web site in our Advertising Network. 

In addition to the ways to opt-out from Pulse Targeted Advertising set forth above, you may contact us with respect to our information collection and opt-out options. Users can email [clientservices@pulse360.com](mailto:clientservices@pulse360.com). 

Users can send mail to the following postal addresses: 

2390 North Forest Road, Suite 10  
Getzville, New York 14068  
U.S.A.  
or call the following telephone number [1-866-94-PULSE (1-866-947-8573)](tel:+18669478573)

We are not responsible for altering the privacy practices of any third party. 

As noted above, we do not collect personal information on our Advertising Network and therefore we do not collect personal information from children under the age of 13 on our Advertising Network. 

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Be sure to visit this page frequently to find any updates we have made. Your continued use of the site after such changes have been posted indicates your consent and acceptance of such changes. 

We retain Non-PII that is used to more effectively match advertisements and website content to your interests for no more than twelve (12) months, after which time such data is deleted. However, aggregate reports generated from such data - as well as data used for other purposes - may be retained for a longer period. 

This Privacy Policy is effective and was last updated on January 06, 2011.
